♪Trapped in this tiny world♪
♪I'm crushed into dust♪
♪I meddle around without any mercy♪
♪I'm my own pawn♪
♪I sigh at my fate♪
♪Numerous people are under my control♪
♪All the sand is washed away♪
♪An old dream fades♪
♪A bumpy path lies ahead♪
♪Traps within traps, I never make mistakes♪
♪I take a risk at every step♪
♪Even in disputes, I break through with my life♪
♪Schemes within schemes, I prison myself♪
♪Each link swaps bluff and truth♪
♪The world is my Weiqi game board♪
♪Everything's just fleeting♪
♪The play begins♪
♪No return is expected♪
♪The flame is gone, whether we win or lose♪
♪The wind never ceases. I hold the reins♪
[Ashes To Crown]
[Adapted from Xixing's novel, Empress of the State of Chu]
[Episode 21]
Zhu Yong is backed by the Grand Princess.
Now, in the Imperial Guard Office,
he's a favorite.
The Imperial Guard Office arrests anyone at will.
Even Mr. Deng...
His Majesty is here.
Kneel.
- Greetings, Your Majesty. - Greetings, Your Majesty.
- Greetings, Your Highness. - Greetings, Your Highness.
Bow.
You may rise.
- Thank you, Your Majesty. - Thank you, Your Majesty.
Your Highness,
I request to go to Huzhou
for the summer flood corruption case.
This is a serious case.
The Commandant of Justice,
the Minister of Revenue,
and the Imperial Guard Office will co-investigate.
Mr. Deng, make the arrangements.
Yes.
Her Highness had the Imperial Guard Office
cooperate with Mr. Deng
[Xie Residence]
instead of being arbitrary.
And Mr. Deng responded
to Her Highness.
Doesn't that mean
he accepts her political interference?
How do I know what she thinks?
Don't you always say
Chu Zhao is just like you?
How do you not know
what she thinks?
Fine.
Then I will
think about it.
Last night, she visited Mr. Deng.
I thought
they would fall out and break up.
Unexpectedly,
they put on an act together.
An act?
For whom?
Me, of course.
In case my clan has sole dominance
and seizes power from His Majesty,
she even supports Mr. Deng
to maintain tripartite balance within the court.
She's clever.
But sadly, she's too soft-hearted.
She wants a stable court.
Then I will let her know
kindness can't survive in this world.
Have Yu Shang send this to the Northern Desert.
It's been years since Zhong Changrong
guarded Xinggu Pass.
He should rest.
If Xinggu Pass is invaded...
So...
We'll have Liang Qiang prepare early.
Greetings, Your Majesty.
You're back, Qi Bo.
You're just in time.
The provisions you brought back last time
are running out.
Go get some more.
Already?
We have three contingents.
They're certainly consumed quickly.
Three?
The Eldest Prince is in the rear,
but he still needs our provisions.
My son is securing the rear.
He must be well-fed.
Don't worry.
I'll get the provisions
as soon as I can.
This time,
I've brought you
a transaction
that is very beneficial.
Interesting.
How interesting.
Xie Yanfang
wants me to kill Zhong Changrong
at Xinggu Pass.
Xiao Xun wants my army
to pass Xiaonan.
These two idiots
both want to court me.
All right.
Then I will fulfill
their wishes.
Your Majesty is wise.
Chu Ling is dead.
The State of Chu has civil strife.
This is exactly our moment.
Issue my order.
Send a troop of soldiers.
I'll show them
how I can benefit
from their own infighting.
[Xinggu Pass]
Don't move, General Liang.
What do you want?
Don't be nervous.
The Northern Desert troops are just passing by.
This is treason!
It isn't.
It's just a deal.
Mr. Xie passed an order.
"Their troops need a victory.
And the victory we give them
will have no impact
on our war situation."
Does Mr. Xie know
what will happen?
He said
the Northern Desert King would send troops.
Zhong Changrong
would die at Xinggu Pass.
Then...
His position
will be yours.
General Liang,
all you need to do
is stand here
and pretend
you didn't see anything.
[Xinggu Pass]
[Changping Pass]
General,
the enemy king decamped
and disappeared.
So far,
no beacon smoke has been seen
throughout Yunzhong.
Could they be
lying in ambush?
From their former encampment
to Yunzhong,
there aren't valleys or depressions
for such a large army
to hide.
Report!
Raid on Xinggu Pass!
Zhong is just patrolling there.
But...
General Zhong's route
is a military secret.
Call up 500 soldiers.
We'll go.
Yes.
General,
this raid is so precise.
Someone must have leaked our route.
Do they think they can
invade us this way?
What a pipe dream!
I'm their target.
General Liang,
the Northern Desert troops passed
through your guarding area.
However perfectly
we carry out this plan,
Zhong Changrong
will suspect you.
When he gets to the bottom,
by then,
even if someone protects you,
you'll have to work in the labor camp
as a guilty person.
Your clan
won't be able to rise again.
So,
what do you want me to do?
You have to kill
all those enemies.
Because
Zhong Changrong's followers
must witness that scene
of valor and tragedy.
Right now,
a squad of several hundred men
is patrolling not far away.
Shoot this whistling arrow.
Our men will lure that squad
over to you.
That way,
your bravery will be witnessed.
And you won't die
while outnumbered.
General Liang,
after you take over
the frontier command,
you'll bring glory to the state
and fortune to people.
Your name will
go down in history.
Charge!
You should be guarding Xinggu Pass.
Why are you here?
I was surveying nearby terrain
and passed by.
Another squad
is coming over.
Hold on, General Zhong.
Take him back! Keep him alive!
- Yes. - Yes.
Mr. Zhong.
Hurry.
Send men to defend Xinggu Pass.
Mr. Zhong.
Light a smoke signal.
Full-scale alert!
Yes.
[Xinggu Pass]
How's General?
His vital organs aren't injured.
But he's bleeding seriously.
I'm afraid...
Keep him alive.
Or I'll kill you.
Yes.
I'll do my best.
General.
Wangcheng is lost.
It's a trap.
Did you have a nightmare?
Shall I take you back
for some rest?
Your Highness,
urgent frontier report.
Wangcheng is lost.
General Zhong is badly injured.
How is Jiu doing?
We don't know the specifics.
Don't worry too much.
When Jiu is there,
the frontier won't fall.
The report only says
enemy troops broke through Xinggu Pass.
Not a word
is about Liang Qiang.
He's the general
guarding Xinggu Pass.
In such a big case,
his condition should be reported,
whether he's dead or missing.
Unless
he's highly suspicious
and many people are involved.
So, at this crucial point,
it must be set aside
to avoid shaking the morale.
Wangcheng is strategically vital!
Once it's lost,
Yunzhong will be in peril!
If Yunzhong is lost,
our state will be in peril!
That's right.
Xie Yanlai bragged that he would
kill the Northern Desert King.
But now, he can't even defend the frontier.
He must be severely punished.
Right!
He lost one city.
Then he may lose another.
How many cities are there
at the frontier?
How could Your Highness trust
such an impetuous man?
Things can't go on like this.
Ministers,
at this point,
what's the use of arguing?
The Northern Desert King sent a message,
asking for peace talks.
I think
we should avoid direct confrontation.
We will
never accept peace talks.
Never?
So will the war continue?
Will we ignore the people in Wangcheng?
The King wants friendly relations
and territorial concessions.
Is this a peace offer?
This is a humiliation.
Countless soldiers shouldn't
die in vain.
My father's decade-long persistence
shouldn't be wasted.
Wangcheng is lost,
but Your Highness is still so stubborn.
What will people think of you?
Why don't you leave the court
and let me handle this?
Mr. Deng, are you saying
I am to blame for the error
of the frontier troops?
Xie Yanlai serves you.
In that case,
you can't shirk the blame.
When I was in charge, the frontier was safe.
After the supervisors you sent there,
especially Liang Qiang you favor,
failed their duties,
the enemies managed to break in.
Your Highness
learned to shift blame.
I would rather say,
I interfered
so late
that frontier troops were too corrupt
to be mended.
Even when Liang Qiang was favored,
he couldn't reverse the decline!
Mr. Deng,
who do you think will benefit
from the failure of frontier troops
and the loss of a city?
You don't think
I used the failure of the troops
and the suffering of the people
to force you
out of the court, do you?
Chu Zhao,
you aren't worthy.
You always claim
you prioritize self-interest.
I thought you were
just saying that for fun.
What a surprise.
You really dared to do that.
Xiaoman.
These are your letters
with frontier troops,
including private letters.
Chu Zhao,
how dare you pry into my privacy?
I just did, so what?
You supervise by late Emperor's order.
I protect the state by his order.
So, I must know
anything that involves
our state affairs.
Take out Mr. Deng's letters
to and from Liang Qiang.
And his letters with other ministers
where they plotted
to depose me.
Yes.
Liang Qiang said
his transfer to Xinggu Pass was improper.
You said
he could just go ahead
and you would take responsibility
if anything went wrong.
Liang Qiang did write me
this letter.
Then I replied like that.
What's wrong?
A frontier general knew it was improper.
And a civil official like you far back in the Capital
insisted on meddling
in military affairs.
So?
So,
you won't come to the court for a while.
Go back home and reflect on yourself.
Good.
Very good.
Let me see
if you can get what you desire
when I'm away from the court.
Xiaoman,
send him back home.
Yes, Your Highness.
Mr. Deng,
how have you been?
Mr. Xie, to what do I
owe this pleasure?
I'm here to apologize.
You took the blame
for the loss of Wangcheng.
I sent the message
to the Northern Desert.
And I asked Liang Qiang
to defect.
As for why the enemies passed through Xiaonan
to attack Wangcheng...
I need not say,
for you know who did that.
Xie Yanfang!
How could you do this
to frontier troops and civilians
at Wangcheng?
They are people of our state.
They'll die a worthy death
to sacrifice for their state.
You can go and turn me in.
However,
who would believe
your one-sided statement?
Fine.
I'll wait and see
what exactly
you are up to.
Well, it's getting late.
I'll take my leave.
I do hope
I can see you again
at the court.
Thinking about what happened?
Be seated, Mr. Xie.
I thought hard, but I don't get it.
If he simply wanted me
to withdraw from the court,
why did he sacrifice the frontier
and civilians in Wangcheng?
This isn't
Deng Yi's style.
Your Highness,
Mr. Deng's desire
has never changed.
I have proof
that Liang Qiang
serves Mr. Deng.
So you think he wants
to command frontier troops?
So, he wanted Mr. Zhong dead
in this raid,
then Liang Qiang would turn the tide
and take command.
To be honest,
it has something to do with Yanlai.
I guess Mr. Deng believed
Yanlai dared to make
that military pledge
because my whole clan
backed him up.
He couldn't bear to see
military power slip.
That's why he took desperate risks
at any cost.
As for Wangcheng...
We are not certain
if he was behind that.
Or maybe
that was merely an accident.
After all, the tides of war always change.
One false move
may lead to the loss of a city.
I don't usually get along with Mr. Deng.
But I refuse to believe
he would collude with our enemies.
Now, the situation is complicated.
For the moment,
our priority
is to stabilize the court.
I know.
He was placed
under house arrest
because he argued with me
on whether to have
peace talks.
As for how we should handle him...
After we take back Wangcheng
and uncover the truth,
we'll know.
Don't worry too much.
The sudden loss of Wangcheng
was truly horrifying.
Fortunately,
Yunzhong led all units
to heavily guard it
and fought the invaders.
Those invaders failed
to advance further.
I have faith in frontier troops.
But how about people in Wangcheng?
If we reject peace talks,
the enemies will threaten us with a massacre.
Peace talks
start with talks.
In that case,
we'll have time to negotiate.
Rest assured.
Soon,
I will ask
relevant ministers
to draft an agenda
for you to review.
Thank you, Mr. Xie.
Mr. Deng has been confined.
At this moment,
I should step up.
You're truly a blessing
for our state.
Don't say that, Your Highness.
In every way,
we're a family.
Tea is good.
But too much tea will upset you.
It's almost lunchtime.
Go have a good lunch with Yu
and get some sleep.
I'm afraid
we're going to confront
tough challenges.
I certainly believe
you're tough-minded enough.
But,
you still need
a healthy body.
Don't panic.
You have me.
Le.
Your Highness.
Recently,
has Xiao Xun behaved?
Precisely.
For nearly half a year,
he hasn't left his house.
Over the last month,
he has stayed indoors,
making his father's birthday gift.
Keep watching.
Yes.
Your Highness,
news just came in.
Mr. Deng was escorted out by the Imperial Guard Office
and then confined in his mansion.
The reason is unknown.
We only know he fought
Her Highness after court.
Your Highness,
this might be our chance.
Before I finish my father's gift,
so much
has already happened in the Capital.
But for me,
nothing matters more
than this Scroll of Longevity
for my father.
It's finally done.
I should go visit Mr. Deng.
How's Xun doing?
Very well.
He's been patient.
He has sent
your birthday gift
to the Imperial Manufactories.
It will be delivered here
with official gifts.
I had intended
to keep the official gifts
outside my prefecture.
Since Xun's gift is among them,
get all those gifts in, then.
Look at this.
[Wangcheng fell at midnight last night, the enmy will soon besiege Yunzhong.]
Wangcheng is lost?
The Northern Desert King
will threaten the court with that city.
For the sake
of thousands of civilians,
the court will have to accept peace talks.
But under such circumstances,
if you send troops against the court,
things might backfire.
Threatening with Wangcheng,
those foes
will get what they want.
They'll also end the war decently.
For them,
that will be a victory.
As for the young emperor,
Chu Zhao, Deng Yi, and Xie Yanfang,
they will lose people's support
as well as their prestige.
By then...
Your prestige will rise greatly.
When you call to arms,
the world will be yours.
[Wangcheng, the north gate]
[Wangcheng]
Help them!
Go. Let's help them!
[Wangcheng]
Stop.
See how many people here
will have to die for you!
General, what do we do?
Bring it on!
Retreat.
General!
I said, retreat!
Losers!
Bring it on!
General,
General Zhong is awake.
According to the Army Physician,
he will survive.
Won't you see him?
Glad he won't die.
What about the mission
I gave you?
Thirty-six soldiers skilled
in disguise
and assassination,
and familiar
with the enemy's capital
are in position.
As you commend,
all has been kept confidential.
Very good.
Move out.
Wangcheng is strategically vital.
Thousands of civilians
are in the hands of enemies.
But Yanlai stays within the camp.
No wonder ministers complain.
A general in war
isn't bound by imperial orders.
I trust him.
I trust him too.
So, when the ministers
wanted to replace him,
I didn't approve.
But to be honest,
I'm a little worried.
Will he
be reckless at this juncture?
Did he really go
to kill the Northern Desert King?
Under such circumstances,
even if Yanlai
manages to kill the King,
the Eldest Prince
will ascend the throne.
He's fierce and warlike,
but not as far-sighted as his father.
By then,
he will invade
in the name of revenge.
His army's morale will soar.
I'm afraid peace talks will be hard.
Is there really no solution
to Wangcheng's problem?
In that case,
I'll have to go to Yunzhong again.
No.
When I go,
I can at least steady the troops.
I'll go instead.
There's something ministers can do,
but a princess can't.
You...
Rest assured.
I will not accept
any of their conditions.
Yu is my hope.
I place great hopes on him
and intend to support him.
When he was little,
he witnessed his parents' brutal death.
He barely survived
and took the throne.
Then rebellion and invasion came.
If he couldn't be
a wise emperor
who expanded his state
and achieved something
beyond his forebears,
it would be unfair to what he suffered.
And accepting peace talks
is a humiliation
to someone like me.
Then, what are you going to do?
Will you trade
the people in Wangcheng
for victory?
How could you think of me that way?
You broke my heart.
Rejecting peace talks
is your idea.
Your reputation
is Yu's reputation.
How could I ever
abandon people in Wangcheng?
It's all right that you don't trust me.
You should have faith in what I can do.
That's right.
I have faith in what you can do.
From tomorrow on,
kill a hundred civilians
on the rampart every day
until the State of Chu accepts
all our conditions.
Yes.
Your Majesty!
Aren't you a follower
of the Eldest Prince?
Why are you here
instead of in our capital?
The Eldest Prince...
He was killed.
What did you say?
It's something my son always keeps.
Some enemy soldiers
invaded our capital
and killed His Highness.
Before His Highness died,
he gave this to me.
I fought my way out
to bring you this news!
You must avenge His Highness!
How dare you curse my son!
Son.
My son.
My son!
[Wangcheng]
Your Majesty.
Oh my son.
When Mr. Xie goes,
he will succeed.
We must teach those foes
a good lesson!
- Yes. - That's right.
Give them a lesson.
- Yes. - Show them what we can do.
Mr. Xie, we'll entrust you
with frontier affairs.
His Majesty and I believe
you will
protect our people
and safeguard our state's dignity.
I will not
fail my mission.
Great news!
Oh no.
Great victory!
Guard General Xie Yanlai
has killed the Eldest Prince of Northern Desert,
broken into the King's camp,
and caught...
Caught the King alive!
My son!
♪Trapped in this tiny world♪
Terrific!
He caught the King alive.
♪I meddle around without any mercy♪
♪I'm my own pawn♪
♪I sigh at my fate♪
Great.
Yes.
This is great.
♪Traps within traps, I never make mistakes♪
♪I take a risk at every step♪
♪The world is my Weiqi game board♪
♪I hold the reins♪
♪Broken walls and withered branches, trapped in the mire♪
♪Yet still striving to reach for the sky♪
♪My pride is torn down and my body is sacrificed♪
♪The spark smolders in the crack♪
♪And roars in the blaze♪
♪Burning the cold night until daybreak♪
♪Fate imprisons me♪
♪But I won't beg the abyss for mercy♪
♪Even if hope is faint, I remain proud♪
♪A mayfly will cross the ocean, however long it takes♪
♪However it ends up, I'll go my own way♪
♪With no fear of the distance♪
♪Born from decay, fireflies still burn♪
♪With sword in hand, I'll pierce the dawn♪
♪Let these scars all over me become♪
♪My new pride♪
♪Peril is everywhere in the palace♪
♪Yet I smile to nobody but you♪
♪Amidst the chaos♪
♪I'll always be with you♪
♪The spark smolders in the crack♪
♪And roars in the blaze♪
♪Burning the cold night until daybreak♪
♪Fate imprisons me♪
♪But I won't beg the abyss for mercy♪
♪Even if hope is faint, I remain proud♪
♪A mayfly will cross the ocean, however long it takes♪
♪However it ends up, I'll go my own way♪
♪With no fear of the distance♪
♪Born from decay, fireflies still burn♪
♪With sword in hand, I'll pierce the dawn♪
♪Let these scars all over me become♪
♪My new pride♪